rugzo.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy « Futura Domains

#### Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy is here to help you understand what information we collect at Futura Domains, how we use it, and what choices you have. When we talk about Futura Domains in this policy, we are talking about the Futura Domains website at www.futuradomains.com. Futura Domains is available for use via a web browser or applications specific to your desktop or mobile device.

#### Information we collect and receive

We collect different kinds of information. Some of it is personally identifiable and some is non-identifying or aggregated. Here are the types of information we collect or receive:  
• Information about your domain name. When Sellers list a domain name on Futura Domains, we retain the information related to that domain name. This may include, but is not limited to, textual descriptions and graphics.  
• Account and profile information. To use the Futura Domains Service we require you to register an account. Basic information that we require of you includes your username, email address, phone number and Paypal or other bank account associated e-mail address. When completing a domain name sale through Futura Domains, users can systematically rate their experience of dealing with the Seller. This “rating” information, displayed in the form of a number, is made available to other Users through the Futura Domains website.  
• Billing information. We only require account-related e-mail addresses to be stored. Sellers are required to provide their bank or Paypal account e-mail address to Futura Domains in order to receive payments. In some instances, if payment is to be made outside of the standard website payment format, additional information may be required to be stored, such as a bank account number, etc.  
• Log data. When you use Futura Domains, our servers automatically record information, including information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. This log data may include your Internet Protocol address, the address of the web page you visited before coming to Futura Domains, your browser type and settings, the date and time of your request, information about your browser configuration and plug-ins, language preferences, and cookie data. Log data does not contain message content and is not routinely deleted.  
• Device information. In addition to log data, we may also collect information about the device you’re using on Futura Domains, including what type of device it is, what operating system you’re using, device settings, unique device identifiers, and crash data. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings.  
• Futura Domains’ usage information: This is information about how you interact with the Futura Domains website.  
• Communication content that you send and receive within Futura Domains. This includes:  
o The message content itself. This content can include messages, pictures, and/or files.  
o When messages or files were sent and by whom, when or if they were seen by you, and where you received them (in a channel or direct message, for example).  
• Information from partners or other 3rd parties. Futura Domains may receive information from partners or others that we could use to make our own information better or more useful. This might be aggregate level information about which IP addresses go with which zip codes or it might be more specific information about how well an online marketing or email campaign performed.

#### Our Cookie Policy

Futura Domains uses cookies, or similar technologies like single-pixel gifs and web beacons, to record log data. We use both session-based and persistent cookies.

Cookies are small text files sent by us to your computer and from your computer to us, each time you visit our website. They are unique to your Futura Domains account or your browser. Session-based cookies last only while your browser is open and are automatically deleted when you close your browser. Persistent cookies last until you or your browser delete them or until they expire.

Some cookies are associated with your Futura Domains account and personal information in order to remember that you are logged in. Other cookies are not tied to your Futura Domains account but are unique and allow us to do site analytics and customization, among other similar things. If you access Futura Domains through your browser, you can manage your cookie settings there but if you disable all cookies you may not be able to use Futura Domains.

Futura Domains sets and accesses its own cookies on its company-owned domains. In addition, we use 3rd parties like Google Analytics for website analytics. We do not currently recognize or respond to browser-initiated Do Not Track signals as there is no consistent industry standard for compliance.

#### How we use your information

We use your information for the following:  
• Providing the Futura Domains service. We use information you provide to authenticate you and deliver message content to you and from you.  
• Understanding and improving our products. To make the product better we have to understand how users are using it. We collect usage data and we intend to use it many different ways to improve our products, including research. This policy is not intended to place any limits on what we do with usage data that is aggregated or de-identified so it is no longer tied to a unique Futura Domains user.  
• Communicating with you:  
o Solving your problems and responding to your requests. If you contact us with a problem or question, we will use your information to respond to that request and address your problems or concerns.  
o In-product communications. We may use the information you provide to contact you through Futura Domains or via email, SMS or text message.  
o Email messages. We may send you service and administrative emails, particularly as they relate to a domain name listing. We may also contact you to inform you about changes in our services, our service offerings and important service related notices, such as changes to this policy or security and fraud notices. These messages are considered part of the service and you may not opt-out of them. In addition, we may send you certain marketing-related messages, from which you can opt out at any time.

#### Sharing and Disclosure

There are times when communications and related content and other user information may be shared by Futura Domains. This section discusses only how Futura Domains may share user information. Futura Domains may share information:  
• With consent, to comply with legal process, or to protect Futura Domains and our Users. When we have your consent or if we believe that disclosure is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation or legal request; to protect the safety, rights, or property of the public, any person, or Futura Domains; or to detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues. If we receive a law enforcement or other third party request for information we will provide prior notice to the subject of the request where we are legally permitted to do so.  
• With third party service providers and agents. We may employ third party companies or individuals to process personal information on our behalf based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy. For example, we may share data with a security consultant to help us get better at preventing unauthorized access or with an email vendor to send messages on our behalf. We may also share data with hosting providers, payment processors, marketing vendors, and other consultants who work on our behalf.

#### Security

Futura Domains takes reasonable steps to protect information you provide to us as part of your use of the Futura Domains service from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access or disclosure. These steps take into account the sensitivity of the information we collect, process and store and the current state of technology. When you enter sensitive information (such as sign-in credentials) we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal data submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. However, no electronic or email transmission or digital storage mechanism is ever fully secure or error free.

#### Children’s information

Futura Domains is not directed to children under 18. If you learn that a minor child has provided us with personal information without your consent, please contact us.

#### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may change this policy from time to time, and if we do we’ll post any changes on this page. If you continue to use Futura Domains after those changes are in effect, you agree to the revised policy. If the changes are material, we may provide more prominent notice or seek your consent to the new policy.

#### Contacting Futura Domains

Please also feel free to contact us if you have any questions about Futura Domains’ Privacy Policy or practices. You may contact us at info@futuradomains.com or using the contact form below:
